#### Contact

+7-921-3882934 (Mobile) samehome@yandex.ru

www.linkedin.com/in/alesavin (LinkedIn) alesavin.ru (Personal)

### Top Skills

Hosting Services
SaaS
Java

### Languages

English (Professional Working)
Russian (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Machine Learning

Big Data Analysis wit

Big Data Analysis with Scala and Spark

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

Principles of Reactive Programming Теория игр (Game Theory)

# Alex Savin

Senior Scala Developer at Addison Global - The Creators of MoPlay Malaga, Andalusia, Spain

## Summary

More than 10 years of experience at software development: started from DevOps role to team leader. I joined Yandex. Classifieds infrastructure at 2011, my core points there were: Java/Scala development, highload architectures, distributed systems for big data/stream processing (Hadoop/Kafka/Spark), search and near topics. At start of 2019 I switched to Spain-located betting company AddisonGlobal with passion on functional programming. I like to build high-quality systems according to The Reactive Manifesto and invest in coaching others to made wonderful things together.

## Experience

Addison Global - The Creators of MoPlay Senior Scala Developer February 2019 - Present Málaga Area, Spain

Ciklum Senior Scala Developer February 2019 - Present Málaga Area, Spain

#### Yandex

7 years 10 months

Senior Software Developer Team Lead November 2015 - January 2019 (3 years 3 months)

Saint Petersburg, Russian Federation

I lead group of developers with designing, developing and support backend for quality and commercial platforms, deal with software tasks at infrastructure team of vertical searches business unit. Prefer reactive programming patterns and Scala/Akka technology stack.

Software Developer April 2011 - December 2015 (4 years 9 months)

#### Saint Petersburg, Russian Federation

Developing Java, Scala services for vertical search on car ads, vacancies and realty offers. In details: 2-4 mln entities depends on service, >1000 partner feeds, fault-tolerant ETL (extract, transform, load) process include feed downloading, data sharding, unification, clusterization, index building, index update on 64 search machines. Hadoop/HBase for statistical tasks, MySQL for analytics. Team share tasks on services for the best replaceability.

Figures: full index update over 15 min, fast search 4000rps 99.9% < 50ms, detailed search 500rps 99% < 500ms.

Technologies: Scala/Akka/Spray, Lucene, Cassandra, HBase, MySQL.

#### Favor-IT

DevOps

April 2008 - April 2011 (3 years 1 month)

Developing, managing and deploying software for water analysis. Full process from workspace organization to production release: infrastructure tasks (VCS/IDE, CI, fault- tolerant network, phone support system, monitoring), hardware selection and installation (common/blade servers, RAID, SuSE linux, network), software development (Java EE, EJB, Servlets, JSP), deploy (self-developed system), product support. Lead (include hiring) personnel of infrastructure group (2 people max).

Technologies: Linux, Java EE, Tomcat, PostgreSQL, Ant.

#### Favor-IT

System Engineer

March 2006 - March 2008 (2 years 1 month)

Managing server farm for the SaaS solution (water analisys). Figures: 2 data centers, >60 machines, >20 services (10-100 users each), SuSE Linux, RAID, fault-tolerant network. Manage emergency switch to slave services or backups (1h outage max).

#### **BizHost**

System Engineer

July 2005 - December 2005 (6 months)

Web hosting, mail hosting. FreeBSB- based virtual hosting with self-developed panel (PHP, MySQL), dedicated hosting. Figures: >10000 sites, 10 machines.

QuoVadis Internet Cafe Administrator June 2003 - June 2005 (2 years 1 month) One of the first Internet cafes at Saint Petersburg. Speaking with clients, solve problems, printing.

# Education

Saint Petersburg State Polytechnical University Master of Science, Computer Science · (2005 - 2006)

Saint Petersburg State Polytechnical University Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (1999 - 2004)